# David Trumble . Jarvis Consulting

My name is David Trumble; a current Software Developer of Jarvis Consulting Group. I have a Diploma in Computer Programming as well as previous industry experience freelancing as both; Full-Stack and WordPress Developer. The software industry is a challenging yet rewarding job scope for myself, it is an opportunity to: have an outlet for my creativity, learn new things, collaborate with like-minded individuals and ultimately work towards something that makes a positive lasting impact.

## Skills

Proficient: C/C++, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/SQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, HTML, CSS, BootStrap, JavaScript, Slack, Notion, VIM

Competent: Java, SQL Developer, Node.js, Postgres, Heroku, IBM i-series/AS400, PuTTY/FileZilla/WinSCP

Familiar: React, Handlebars, Sequalize, WordPress, PHP, Python, JUCE, Arduino, Control Language, MongoDB, SSH/SCP/SFTP, Windows/Powershell, XAMPP, Riverbed, UML, Rational Rose, StarUML, Sketch

## **Jarvis Projects**

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis\_data\_eng\_DavidTrumble

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: This project uses Google Cloud Platform(Compute Engine) to initialize a Virtual Machine with CentOS. Within the Virtual Machine, an instance of Docker is provisioned. A Postgresql instance is then provisioned on Docker. Data is inserted via an automated Bash/Shell script and retrieved from the RDBMS with SQL; which details hardware specifications.

### Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- JDBC App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.
- Grep App: Curabitur laoreet tristique leo, eget suscipit nisi. Sed in sodales ex. Maecenas vitae tincidunt dui, et eleifend quam.

#### Highlighted Projects

**3-Band Equalizer** [GitHub]: Virtual Studio Technology - Low Cut, High Cut and Parametric Equalizer with Frequency and Gain control.

Database Manager [GitHub]: Database storage, input and retrieval for Ministry of Health of Ontario vaccine counts.

**Typing Tutor** [GitHub]: Helps users learn typing without looking at keys. Has onscreen keyboard display and highlights keys that are being pressed

Weighted Learning - Rock Paper Scissors [GitHub]: Creates a simulation between 2 AI opponents in a game of Rock, Paper, Scissors; then weighs the results to determine future decisions.

Quantifying Gravitational Force [GitHub]: Receive user input then quantifies the Neutrons of Gravitational Force between 2 objects on Earth.

## **Professional Experiences**

Software Developer, Jarvis (2021-present): Serve as a member and lead of the software development team. Facilitate proper design and implementation of software. Provide detailed and innovative design; creating a seamless software experience.

Full-Stack Developer, Freelance - https://stormy-plateau-32984.herokuapp.com/ (2021): Provided Front-End website architecture, user interactions on it's web page and end-to-end service. Also, developed Back-End and managed server functionality; ensuring cross-platform optimization for mobile phones.

WordPress Developer, Freelance - https://coast.edwincheungdesign.com/ (2020): Established and guided the websites architecture to ensure high-performance and availability; while creating extra utility functions via programming

PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML/CSS. Managed and formulated effective, responsive designs and converted them to a working theme as a customizable, open-source eCommerce platform.

Program Coordinator & Audio Engineer, The Noize Faktory (2014-2019): Prepared and documented all new client contracts, registrations and payments for new and on-going studio services. Instructed individual and group tutorials in: recording, production, theoretical acoustics, music composition, mixing and mastering.

Account Manager & Arrears Account Specialist, Captial One (2008-2009, 2012-2013): Presented, chartered and managed concerns with account holders and employed timely solutions. Determined the validity of client statements and advised client of file procedures; clearly documenting call results and consumer account communications.

Marketing Sales Representative, CanEAST Communications (2009-2010): Developed product-relevant presentations for individuals, families, large groups and businesses. Directed sales inquiries, pricing and information as first point of contact for new and potential customers.

#### Education

Seneca College (2018-2021), Diploma, Computer Programming

Recording Arts Canada (2014-2015), Certificate, Audio Engineering

Seneca College (2012-2013), Certificate, General Arts

Seneca College (2010-2012), Incomplete, Business Administration - Marketing

#### Miscellaneous

- 3rd Dan Kukkiwon
- Winner
- Reading
- Music
- Exercise